Well, it's official. My first stock sale
in a very long period of time has gone
out, which means yes, I sent a sell
alert to everybody in the course live
stream, but you are going to learn about
it in this video.
Uh
>> [sighs]
>> I hate to say it, but it has nothing to
do with the market. Yeah, the market, at
least the Nasdaq 100, has turned red
today after being green this morning,
which is interesting, but it's probably
because the last 2 days we had this
crazy leverage buy up in the markets,
and so short-term that euphoria probably
wasn't going to last. In fact, this
morning our alpha report, while the
market was still green, said, quote,
"While it's possible the fund keeps
going, Monday and yesterday were so
strong, it would make sense for the
market to chill, especially a day or two
before the BLS jobs data. And even if it
does move up today, it's a 10-point
schlog to the next line of QQQ at 7:35,
which means we have a less ideal outlook
for the market." That is just an example
of our alpha report, and as you can see,
the market did end up bleeding today.
You can always join us at meetkevin.com,
but this video is actually about selling
all exposure to a stock that I was
really excited about. And this
particular stock also has implications
for others. The others being PayPal and
Block. I didn't have any exposure to
them, but the reason I sold
Circle stock
is also something that is going to
affect these guys. Now, to take a small
haircut on this, cost basis was right
around the seven number. Okay, so sold
around 61, cost basis around the 70-ish
number.
Um oh well, the uh this stock actually
did run up quite a bit after I bought
it. Uh it was all the way up to like 120
for a while, but that short-term
momentum wasn't taken advantage of by me
because I had a lot of faith in the
long-term for this puppy. And
unfortunately, that long-term got
U-turned not by what you might think,
which would be OUSD,
and not by the banking charter they got,
which we'll talk about that in just a
moment, but actually something that the
Federal Reserve is doing. So, while I'm
a little paper hander B, long-term still
adding, still buying the dip,
short-term,
it's normal for the market to move down
today after two crazy days yesterday,
but let's talk about what happened with
Circle stock. And always remember, if
you want these alerts before anybody
else, come join us over at
meetkevin.com. You get the lifetime
access to the Alpha membership as well,
and most people write this off on their
taxes. Talk to your CPA and join using
that coupon code we've got now.
The single existential
threat that I think exists for Circle is
the very reason I got
excited about Circle in the first place.
That Circle would be able to build out
infrastructure that would enable 24/7
instantaneous payments. Now, in
fairness, the new risk that we have
doesn't solve international and
cross-border payments, but
the new risk totally solves
instantaneous 24/7 payments. And it's
actually a risk that I talked about in
this video. I made this video in
December of 2022,
back when I still had a really colorful
studio instead of this dark soulless
studio.
But anyway, I wrote crypto to zero, the
Fed's new crypto replacement. And
[laughter] so we made this little tweet
here, Fed Federal Reserve ending crypto.
But in this, I talked about how
the Federal Reserve's FedNow system has
the real potential of destroying the
need for instantaneous 24/7
transactions from stable coins because
you could then just do it within the
banking system.
Okay.
Back then, I thought
it's going to take a freaking decade for
the Fed to do this. Stable coins will
take off before then, and they'll even
help us settle stock transactions. So
much potential for smart contracts.
Unfortunately, I've got bad news on all
of this.
>> [laughter]
>> Regrettably, it means I had to turn into
a little paper-handing weenie baby. I
feel bad about that, but it's the truth.
Now, earnings for this company, Circle,
were pretty boring. Nothing exciting
here. Revenue missed by 1.6%. USD
DC in circulation still up 25%
year-over-year. EPS was in line.
USDC is still the second biggest stable
coin. You know, other launches from
companies like PayPal haven't gained any
traction at all. Who cares? This
actually should be bullish Circle,
right? It is. Nobody else has been able
to hold a candle.
OUSD, which is the consortium of 140
partners creating a pass-through income
model for the partners, where basically
the reserves income that Circle
generates for people holding USDC, that
money instead of going to Circle
shareholders, if you use OS OUSD, would
just go to companies like Visa or the
other institutions partnering with the
OUSD platform. Which is probably the
biggest threat to Tether and USDC, but
you know, we've seen big threats to them
before, and it hasn't really done
anything. People are used to using
Tether. people are used to using
USDC.
But that's not the risk, in my opinion.
I'm less concerned about earnings. I'm
not really concerned about OUSD.
You know, OUSD
could end up flopping and doing nothing.
And who knows, maybe Circle stock after
I make this video will meme and people
will make those like Jim Cramer memes
and be like, "Ha, inverse Kevin."
Fine. But I'm going to have the balls to
tell you about what I'm most concerned
about and it is this right here. It's
called FedNow. This is from my video uh
well, 3 years, four coming up on 4 years
ago now. And FedNow, which offers
instantaneous 24/7 clearing by the
Federal Reserve of bank transactions,
basically think free 24/7 wires, I
thought would take a very long time to
come around, but let's just say it's
>> [sighs]
>> it's already shown up.
So, I just got this email not too long
ago. And I'm not going to mention the
bank here because they asked me not to.
But take a look at this. Hi Kevin, "Some
payments just can't wait for the next
business day. You now have exclusive
early access to real-time payments, RTP,
a new way to send funds instantaneously,
24 hours a day, 7 days a week, 365 days
a year, on weekends and on holidays.
Just like ACH and domestic wires, except
every single day, no wire cutoff time
frame, and they're free." Now,
technically, the back rails aren't free.
The banks have to pay for this, so the
banks subsidize this. But so far, pretty
much all the banks have been subsidizing
this
and they pay it for for their customers.
So,
you know, this is kind of interesting.
This creates some potential issues. Why?
Well, because stablecoins were supposed
to do exactly this.
Now, stable coins can still do this
cross-border and internationally. I
don't think that's going to change, but
I think
that won't last. I think we'll get to
cross-border with FedNow as well, and it
really leaves the stable coins with
hopes that they'll be useful for agentic
commerce and automated peer-to-peer
smart contract-based
transactions. But, I've got concerns for
that, too.
>> [laughter]
>> So,
uh my end of 2022 thesis is coming a lot
faster than I thought. FedNow is
basically very bearish for stable coins.
Circle had the chance to become a
leading partner for this consortium.
Obviously, they got missed because the
pass-through model would crush Circle's
revenue anyway.
Uh which really leaves stable coins as
either instantaneous transaction tools,
which we just lost all domestic needs
for that with FedNow, and this is
gaining in popularity way faster than I
thought. International, I suspect will
come over time, especially since the
very language that FedNow uses is a
language that coordinates and
incorporates Swift transaction language,
which is what we use for international
transactions. Great. Fantastic. So, you
know, the writing is on the wall that
that is coming, right? We're trying to
be ahead of this. I feel like I feel
like I was holding a Sears here.
And so, then I'm like, "Okay, that's not
good." So,
what's the fundamental value of this?
Like, you know, is there is there a book
value we could look at? You know, I I
always like considering book value. You
know, I look at like, "Hey, what's
what's the the market value of the
assets they have?" And that's when you
take the book value, and then you mark
things to market. So, you know, some
things like real estate you have to mark
to market.
Uh things like securities are already
marked to market. So, you look at a
balance sheet and you go, "Okay, well,
what do I think all the office chairs
are worth, the stocks they hold, the
real estate they hold, right?"
Uh
yeah, I mean, you could cheat. You could
look at shareholder equity, you could
look at cash.
And then you look and you go, "All
right, we got a $14 billion company with
maybe 1 and 1/2 billion dollars of free
cash after bills to pay, maybe 3 and 1/2
billion dollars of shareholder equity.
Not really any kind of real estate to
write up to market." So, you're not
really paying book value for this
company. You're paying a multiple of
book value, probably four to five x
multiple of book value for the company.
The company's earnings have grown by 6
and 1/2% on revenue.
But wait a minute. What So, let me
clarify that. Their their revenue has
grown 6 and 1/2%. Um their income has
grown 6 and 1/2% on USD circulation
going up 25%.
So, we have 25% more USD C circulation,
but only 6 and 1/2% more revenue. Some
of that is due to the Federal Reserve
cutting rates,
but that is indicative of relatively
weak pricing power.
And so,
then you get to earnings, and we've got
about a buck of earnings expected for
the end of the year, which means right
now you're paying about 62 times
earnings.
Which you could justify if there was a
really big growth narrative,
but to me, the growth story for stable
coins
just died.
Which was instantaneous payments. Fed
Fed Now is doing it. And and I think
this has a red flag risk for companies
like PayPal and Venmo as well. Now, in
fairness, only about 5% of PayPal's
revenue comes from Venmo transactions.
It's going to be a little bit more if
you add in PayPal transactions. And who
who knows? I could be really wrong about
all this,
but I kind of think what will happen is
FedNow will end up replacing all
peer-to-peer transactions.
See, think about Zelle for example.
Okay, cool. We've got Zelle, but you
have a $500 limit, he's got a $2,000
limit, they've got a $5,000 limit. It's
annoying.
Zelle is really hard to use as a
business owner because the transaction
limits suck. And then they reset the
next day. It's a pain in the butt. Now,
a lot of that is because of the banking
system, not necessarily the rails, but
the FedNow limits are 100,000 to 10
million as as like the upper limits. You
could send We just tested it and sent
$2,500 instantaneously with it. I was
like, "Well, damn. That was a whole lot
easier than Zelle." You don't have to
worry about Zelle as And not every bank
uses Zelle. Now, in fairness, like 2,600
banks use Zelle and like 1,800 use
FedNow, but the Zelle adoption growth
rate has really slowed and the adoption
rate for FedNow is exploding. So, I I'm
convinced FedNow is going to blow past
the uh
uh you know, Zelle service. I think
Zelle will end up dying to FedNow or
they'll just rebrand it and the rails
will be FedNow. Uh this creates actual
real risks for having to use other apps
like a Cash App, Venmo, PayPal for
people who do have banks bank accounts.
Yes, there are people who are unbanked
who like using the apps. Totally fair. I
get that.
But, if I can instantaneously send money
from my bank account 24/7, what do I
need to use PayPal anymore and make sure
I transfer money from my bank to PayPal
or back and forth? What do I need to do
with that for? It's an extra step. It's
an extra app. I don't need that crap
anymore. FedNow cuts it out.
FedNow, instantaneous peer-to-peer
payments.
No cost.
Right from the bank account. It's
literally like
you know, Pay Pal-ing 100,000, a million
bucks. Instantaneous. It's It's an
instant wire. It's great.
Now again, it only works domestically.
And I'm not trying to shill for the Fed,
you know, it's not like I'm
>> [laughter]
>> As we've got the St. Louis Federal
Reserve shirt on.
Ah, people are going to be like, "Kevin,
>> [sighs]
>> get off the Fed's payroll."
>> [laughter]
>> I'm not on the Fed's payroll. Now, if
they asked me to be the Fed chair, I
would consider it.
>> [laughter]
>> We got to go.
Uh, but uh
Anyway,
uh so so then there's another thesis,
you know, well, what about stablecoin
usage for like stock settlement?
T plus zero is basically already coming,
except it's coming through real-time
gross settlement, RTGS. Basically, the
legacy banking system catching up. Don't
even need stablecoins. The problem with
stablecoins is you have to take US
dollar, turn it into a stablecoin, and
then turn it back to US dollar.
I cuz I don't want your stablecoin. I
want the dollars, you know? And And And
we know dollars are a depreciating
asset, but if dollars depreciate, then
so do stablecoins.
It's technically not stable cuz the
value of the dollar fluctuates, and
stablecoins just mirror the dollar.
That's why you buy assets. That's why
you buy stocks. That's why you buy real
estate, you know, whatever whatever
floats your boat.
So, these instantaneous
uh transactions work through um these
real-time payments work through the
Federal Reserve through a language
called uh ISO uh 222
20022. It's a basic finance language,
but uh FedNow is federally regulated.
Stablecoins can use this uh ISO 222 as
well.
But, the
integration of stablecoins still
requires fiat to stable coin to fiat.
And is that necessary?
That's the big question.
So, now we're doing stock settlement T+0
without stable coins.
The banking system is doing
instantaneous 24/7 payments without
stable coins.
So, you're left with international.
But pricing power for that is already
collapsing, at least based on the latest
revenue and earnings margins, which
isn't great.
So, then people say, "But Kevin,
US
uh you know what? Circle USDC, they just
got a banking license. Maybe they can
get into lending."
False.
Their banking license is a very limited
trust bank for holding assets,
not a commercial lending institution.
So, then what's the bull case from the
CEO? Well, the CEO's bull case is smart
contracts.
The FedNow system doesn't do automation
or smart contracts or agent-driven
payments.
Fair.
And that is an issue for now until
FedNow deals with it. Why? Because the
CEO's bull case is agentic AI is going
to use the Circle stable coin to send
money.
I don't know about you, but I don't want
any AI sending my money anywhere
autonomously. And I don't think anybody
wants that. So, you're going to always
have a human in the loop.
But if you're going to have a human in
the loop,
then what you're really doing is having
agents algorithmically,
they're not even really AI anymore,
they're just algorithms, they're
formulas, they're rules-based systems
like smart contracts.
But you would just have those rules or
automations inside of banking portals or
inside of QuickBooks or SoFi or whatever
you're using. And then, you know, you
look and you go, "Yeah, I'll approve
that. I'll deny that. Whatever." It's
just having like an agent set it up for
you, and then you you it.
You don't care if the rail is a stable
coin or FedNow.
And that's the problem.
Bye-bye pricing power for the stable
coin because the banks are just going to
use the federally regulated system
that's
up and running. FedNow.
I think. I could be wrong.
Seven out of 10 top banks are using
FedNow already. 1,800 banks and credit
unions are using it. Half of all US
savings and checking accounts have
access to FedNow, whether you know it or
not. Transactions are up 85% year over
year, but I mean that's coming from a
small base, you know, it's like 30,000
transactions a day. Big deal, it's like
11 million a year.
But that's the problem.
It's growing. You know, Zelle does
billions of transactions in fairness,
but but I think the growth rate is going
to explode for FedNow.
To me, m- maybe it's early. Maybe I'm
wrong. Average transaction size right
now for FedNow usage is 101,000. So
right now, we're we're doing big
transactions with FedNow.
My opinion is it's coming for smalls. I
could be wrong. If the average doesn't
decline over the next year, maybe I'll
be wrong.
But the whole sales pitch for stable
coins was instantaneous 24/7.
Scheiße, now the Fed's doing it.
I actually think because the Fed's doing
it and it's backed by the Treasury, the
government is probably going to start
using this for transfer payments.
VA benefits, social security,
disability, whatever. Here's your
automatic instantaneous FedNow deposit.
Don't have to wait for the freaking
check to clear anymore.
I bet you eventually it'll get used for
payroll.
Hey, my boss is sending payroll at
5:00 p.m. I don't have to wait for the
check to clear anymore. It's not going
to show up on Monday cuz it's after
banking hours.
It's there at 5:01. Actually, no, it's
there at 5:00.
>> [laughter]
>> Cuz it's instant.
So I think this is going to become
mainstream very fast.
Uh I don't think the smart contract
argument is very useful. I think I kind
of think that's like saying, you know,
oh well, we need smart contracts instead
of
Foundry and Ontology at Palantir.
I don't think so.
Uh any pro- programmatic requirements
that smart contracts can provide can
just be done with human-in-the-loop
conditional logic in any banking app or
portal or whatever.
So,
unfortunately, I think Circle
might end up being like a Sears.
And I hate saying that. Took a little
bit of a haircut. It wasn't huge. Could
have sold it for a profit.
Coulda, woulda, shoulda.
Yeah, I'm a little paper-handing pansy.
And maybe you'll be able to meme me as a
Jim Cramer suit cuz this thing doubles
in value, and then everybody's going to
make fun of me for having sold it.
But,
I'm giving you my fundamental take on
it.
Um
I guess we'll see what happens.
And remember, if you want these alerts
and this analysis first before everybody
else, come join us over at
meetkevin.com.
You pay once, you get lifetime access to
the trade alerts, the alpha reports, the
courses on building your wealth. You
probably write it off on your taxes.
>> [music]
>> And you get the fundamental analysis
that we do pretty much every day the
market is open as long as I'm not on
vacation. But, you get the vacation
calendar.
>> [laughter]
>> All right, folks. Thanks for being here.
We'll see you in the next one. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
>> Why not advertise these things that you
told us here? I feel like nobody else
knows about this.
>> We'll We'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You have done so
much. People love you. People look up to
you.
>> Kevin Paffrath, a financial analyst and
YouTuber, Meet Kevin. Always great to
get your take. [music]